Guida West Papers, 1946-2006
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES IX. SUBJECT FILES
  - Welfare (Box 76)
    - Native Americans, 1970-73 (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Reform (Box 79)
      - 1967-79 (Box 79, Folder 5)
      - 1980-2004, undated (Box 79, Folder 6-8)
    - Revenue sharing (Box 79, Folder 9)
    - Social Security, 1969-2005 (Box 79, Folder 10)
    - Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (TANF) (Box 79)
      - General (Box 79)
        - 1996-2000 (Box 79, Folder 11)
        - 2001, undated (Box 80, Folder 1)
      - "Five Years After Welfare Reform: An Agenda for Reauthorization" by Ron Haskins and Rebecca M. Blank, undated (Box 80, Folder 2)
      - Legislation, Mink-Wellstone, 2001 (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Time limits, 1986, 2000-01 (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Work (Box 80)
      - General, 1967-77, 1995-2002, undated (Box 80, Folder 5-9)
      - "Encouraging Work, Reducing Poverty: The Impact of Work Incentive Programs," Manpower Demonstration Research Corporation, Mar 2000 (Box 80, Folder 10)
      - "Women, Welfare and Enterprise," American Enterprise Institute, 1983 (Box 80, Folder 11)
  - Women (Box 80)
    - General (Box 80)
      - 1968-77 (Box 80, Folder 12)
      - 1978-2001, undated (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Eleanor Smeal Report, 1983-84 (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Slims American Women's Opinion Poll, 1970-74 (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - Work (Box 81)
      - General (Box 81)
        - 1970-89 (Box 81, Folder 4-8)
        - 1990-99, undated (Box 82, Folder 1-2)
      - Non-traditional jobs, 1972-80, undated (Box 82, Folder 3-4)
      - Working mothers, 1970-2002, undated (Box 82, Folder 5)
  - Work (Box 82)
    - General, 1966-2001, undated (Box 82, Folder 6-7)
    - "Building a Ladder to Jobs and Higher Wages: A Report by the Working Group on New York City's Low-Wage Labor Market," Oct 2000 (Box 82, Folder 8)
- SERIES X. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS AND COMPUTER MEDIA
  [Digital audio files can be made available on request-please consult the SSC staff. Original audiovisual materials are closed to research.]
  - [Full transcripts of or detailed notes on many of these interviews, conferences, and meetings can be found in SERIES V. INDIVIDUALS, SERIES VI. ORGANIZATION FILES, and SERIES VIII. WRITINGS] (Box 82)
  - Audiocassettes--reformatted (Box 82)
    [CLOSED--digital audio files are available. See Appendix]
  - Tapes 1-187 (Box 83-92)
  - Audiocassettes-not reformatted (Box 83-92)
    [CLOSED]
  - Kergyma II, United Church of Christ Office of Communication [1 cassette], Jan 1973 (Box 83-92)
  - "Talk of the Nation," National Public Radio program, series on Poverty in America [10 cassettes], 24-27 Feb 1992 (Box 83-92)
  - "All Things Considered," National Public Radio program for 15 Nov 1995 with coverage of White House welfare rally (WC100) [2 cassettes] (Box 83-92)
  - Videotapes (VHS) (Box 83-92)
    - NewsTalk Televsion, Afternoon Edition, panel with teens and Rita Jensen, [1 VHS, copyright Multimedia Entertainment] 29 Sep 1996 (Box 93)
    - No Exception: Welfare Made a Difference, [1 VHS] 2002 (Box 93)
    - Welfare Made A Difference: Investing in People to End Poverty, Community Media Project, [1 VHS 6:30] undated (Box 93)
  - Computer disks (Box 93)
    - 8" disks (6) transcripts of interviews with Welfare Rights leaders, 1984 (Box 93)
    - 5 ¼" disks (101): teaching materials from Rutgers, organization files, speeches, writings, research files, 1983-90 (Box 93)
    - 3 ½" disks (26): organization files, writings, 1995-2001 (Box 93)
- SERIES XI. ARTIFACTS
  - Buttons (Box 93)
    - "Child care not war fare" (Box 94, Folder 1)
    - Children's March for Survival, Washington, DC, 25 Mar [1972] (Box 94)
    - Housing First! Affordable Housing for All New Yorkers (Box 94)
    - Hunger Action Network of New York State, "End hunger now" (Box 94)
    - "I Vote to End Homelessness" (Box 94)
    - March on Washington, November 15, 1969 (Box 94)
    - National Welfare Rights Organization (Box 94)
      - "Adequate income now" (Box 94, Folder 2)
      - "$5,500 or fight" (Box 94)
      - "People before politics, NWRO Conference, Miami Beach," 1972 (Box 94)
      - "Welfare Rights NOW!" (Box 94)
    - National Welfare Rights Union, "Real jobs and benefits and guaranteed income now" button (Box 94)
    - New Jersey Fall Mobilization Against Hunger, "Welfare, not warfare" (Box 94)
    - "Nixon doesn't care" (Box 94)
    - "Poor People's Campaign," 1968 (Box 94, Folder 3)
    - "Take the rich off welfare" (Box 94)
    - Women's Committee of One Hundred, "Veto the Welfare Bill" (Box 94)
    - Women, Work and Welfare, Housing Committee, May Day, No Housing! (Box 94)
    - No Peace! Up and Out of Poverty Now! 1990 (Box 94)
  - Conference tickets and badges, NWRO Convention, 1971, 1972 (Box 94, Folder 4)
  - Name badge, Women's Committee of One Hundred (Box 94)
  - Pendant, broken chain link, NWRO (Box 94, Folder 5)
  - Postcard, "Welfare mothers are not born. They are made by unpaid child support and unfair wages." (Box 94, Folder 6)
  - Stickers (Box 94)
  - [see also OVERSIZE] (Box 94)
    - Ferne Sales Company, "Women Power" (Box 94, Folder 7)
    - National Abortion Rights Action League, "I Vote Pro-Choice" (Box 94)
    - National Organization for Women (Box 94)
      - "Elect Women For a Change" (Box 94)
      - "Keep your laws off my body" (Box 94)
      - "Stop the War on the Poor" (Box 94)
    - National Welfare Rights Organization, "Stop the war on the poor". (Box 94)
    - Women's Agenda of New Jersey (Box 94)
    - Workers Association for Guaranteed Employment, "Jobs & Justice" (Box 94)
  - Address stamp, Women's Committee of One Hundred (Box 95)
  - T-shirt, NWRO, "Link up the struggles" (Box 95)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - SERIES III. PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES
    - Federation of Protestant Welfare Agencies: poster drafted by Guida West for Joint Federations Public Policy Partnership ("We Believe…"), Oct 1990 (Box 96, Folder 1)
  - SERIES IV. CONFERENCES AND MEETINGS
    - "Interfaith Strategy Consultation on Welfare Reform," Washington Interrelgious Staff Council, 30-31 Jan 1973: Vantage Point (Box 96, Folder 2)
    - New Jersey Women's Meeting for the Observance of International Women's Year, 17-19 Jun 1977: conference folder and bumper stickers (Box 96, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous conference posters, 1988, undated (Box 96, Folder 4)
  - SERIES V. INDIVIDUALS
    - Duncan, Ruby: printout of transcript of 1984 interview with notes for transcript editing style (Box 96, Folder 5)
    - Stevens, Dottie: Stevens for Governor poster, 1990 (Box 96, Folder 6)
  - SERIES VI. ORGANIZATIONS FILES
    - Association of Community Organizations for Reform Now (ACORN): newsletter, USA (United States of ACORN), 1984-87 (Box 96, Folder 7)
    - Clark County (NV) Welfare Rights Organization: newsletter, Community Press, Jun 1974 (Box 96, Folder 8)
    - Coalition for Basic Human Needs: CBHN Newsletter, Jan 1980 (Box 96, Folder 9)
    - Crusade Against Hunger: newsletter, The Crusader, fall 1971 (Box 96, Folder 10)
    - HumanServe Fund: Update, spring 1984 (Box 96, Folder 11)
    - Interreligious Foundation for Community Organization (IFCO) (Box 96)
      - Newsletter, IFCO News [incomplete], 1972-74 (Box 96, Folder 12-14)
      - Akwesasne Notes, Vol 7, No. 5, joint issue with IFCO News, early winter, 1975 (Box 96, Folder 15)
    - Jobs For the Future: newsletter, Making A Difference, Issue 2, summer 1989 (Box 96, Folder 16)
    - Metuchen-Edison Community Service Committee for the Kilmer Job Corps Center: Jobs Corps newsletter The Corpsman, 1965-66 (Box 96, Folder 17)
    - Movement for Economic Justice: sign and press release from 11 May 1978 Day of Action (Box 96, Folder 18)
    - National Caucus of Labor Committees: newsletter, New Solidarity, Oct-Nov 1972 (Box 96, Folder 19)
    - National Council of Churches: newsletters, The Interchurch News, Mar 1968; Tempo, 1 Feb 1969; EcuLink, summer 2000 (Box 96, Folder 20)
    - National Unemployed and Welfare Rights Organization: The Organizer, Aug 1973 (Box 97, Folder 1)
    - National Welfare Rights Organization (Box 97)
      - Posters and advertisements, 1969-70, undated (Box 97, Folder 2)
      - Publications, The Welfare Fighter [incomplete], 1969-73 (Box 97, Folder 3-7)
    - National Welfare Rights Union/Women's International League for Peace and Freedom/Health Care-We Gotta Have It!: "Who Gets Welfare?" posters, Oct 1995 (Box 98, Folder 1)
    - New York Urban Coalition: newsletter, Urban Rights, 1971 (Box 98, Folder 2)
    - Rutgers University, Extension Division: Urban New Jersey: A Digest of Urban Problems, No. 2-4, 1969-71 (Box 98, Folder 3)
    - United Church of Christ, United Church Board for Homeland Missions, Welfare Priority Team: chart comparing 1971 Federal welfare reform proposals, Apr 1971 (Box 98, Folder 4)
    - Welfare Warriors: newsletter, Welfare Mothers Voice, 1988-89 (Box 98, Folder 5)
    - Women, Work and Welfare: newsletter, Up and Out of Poverty, Vol 2, # 2, spr 1990 (Box 98, Folder 6)
    - Women's Committee of One Hundred: "Why Every Woman in America Should Beware of Welfare Cuts," New York Times advertisement, 8 Aug 1995 (Box 98, Folder 7)
  - SERIES VIII. WRITINGS
    - The National Welfare Rights Movement: The Social Protest of Poor Women: list of NWRO supporters, undated (Box 98, Folder 8)
  - SERIES IX. SUBJECT FILES
    - Daily World, [miscellaneous issues] 1971-72 (Box 98, Folder 9)
    - The Militant [women's conference launches national abortion campaign], 30 Jul 1971 (Box 98, Folder 10)
  - MISCELLANEOUS
    - "Somethin' botherin' you friends…?" campaign literature against George Wallace, National Coordinating Committee for Trade Union Action & Democracy, circa 1972 (Box 98, Folder 11)
    - No Turkeys "Retire Reagan Vote Mondale Ferraro" bumper sticker, 1984; "If he told the truth, he wouldn't be President" campaign literature against George W. Bush, 2004 (Box 98, Folder 12)
    - "Indian Power!" bumper sticker, United Native Americans, undated (Box 98, Folder 13)
  - SERIES IV. CONFERENCES AND MEETINGS
    - "Carrying the Torch: Women in the Civil Rights Movement, 1941-1965" Oct 1988: poster (Map-case Drawer 37)
    - SERIES VI. ORGANIZATIONS FILES
      - Crusade Against Hunger: poster for National School Lunch Week, 1970 (Map-case Drawer 37)
      - Movement for Economic Justice: poster from Tax Justice Project, "Fair Taxation or New Representation," [2 copies] n.d (Map-case Drawer 37)
      - National Welfare Rights Organization (Map-case Drawer 37)
        - "Live Like a Dog December 1-7, test President Nixon's Welfare Plan": poster [2 copies],1969? (Map-case Drawer 37)
        - "How an American Child dies" NY Times advertisement, 21 Dec 1969 (Map-case Drawer 37)
        - "Strategies for Survival" Convention 1973: poster (Map-case Drawer 37)
      - New York Coalition for Children's Survival: series of four posters, undated (Map-case Drawer 37)
      - United Community Corporation: The Crusader!, Newark's Voice for Community Action, first issue, Nov 1966 (Map-case Drawer 37)
      - Welfare Rights Organization: Twenty Years of Struggle: two posters, 1986 (Map-case Drawer 37)
    - MISCELLANEOUS
      - Emergency Campaign to Protect America's Children, Parents, Families: New York Times advertisement, 11 Dec 1995 (Map-case Drawer 37)
      - Flip chart pages for meeting about welfare administration in New Jersey, undated (Map-case Drawer 37)
      - Conselho Estudial de Condição Feminina (Council on the Status of Women), Sao Paolo, Brazil: 2 posters, 1984, undated (Map-case Drawer 37)
      - Conselho Nacional Dos Direitos Da Mulher (National Council on the Rights of Women), Brazil: 2 posters, undated (Map-case Drawer 37)
      - Asociacion de Mujeres de El Salvador (AMES): poster for first Congress, 1984 (Map-case Drawer 37)
      - "Urban Crisis" banner (Map-case Drawer 37)